Tamal Bhattacharya

UI TECHNICAL LEAD

+44-7405854918

△ bhattacharya.tamal@gmail.com

Empowering the user through simple yet elegant UI to create a smooth and wonderful experience.

SKILLS

Angular2

React

Redux

JavaScript

Jest

HTML5

CSS

Android

Java

Agile

GIT

JIRA

Appcelerator

BREW

DOMAIN

Banking and Financial

Travel and Hospitality

Retail

Energy and Utilities

Insurance

EXPERIENCE SUMMARY

10 years of experience in UI and mobility domain working with high profile companies. Worked across multiple geographies like U.S.A, U.K, Japan, China and Singapore. Delivered quality project for brands like JPMorgan & Chase, Barclays, American Express, British Airways, Enterprise Holdings, Chubb, British Gas, Rentokil. Exposure to varied domains – Banking, Insurance, Travel & Hospitality. Proficient of leading teams (onshore and offshore). Exposure to project management tasks such as estimation, resource loading and project planning.

TECHNOLOGY SPECIALIST • COGNIZANT TECHNOLOGY SOLUTIONS • OCT 2017 - TILL DATE

LOCATION: UK.

Working as UI technical lead for a prestigious banking client in Agile scrum. Contributed as UI technical lead with team size of 30 members for an international hospitality brand.

Played the role of a single point of contact for customer at client location and offshore liaison.

Experienced in project management activities like Project Planning, Estimation, Resourcing, Risk and Issue tracking

Practiced Agile methodologies in project execution.

TECHNICAL LEAD • COGNIZANT TECHNOLOGY SOLUTIONS •

JUL 2013 – SEP 2017 LOCATION: India, UK.

Worked as technical/team lead for one of the largest airline logo in the UK. Played the role of senior developer for an international car rental brand delivering user facing applications.

Was instrumental in migrating applications from native to cross platform technology for a major insurance client across APAC region.

Contributed in the capacity of a solo developer for an Energy Utilities giant in the UK

Worked on client facing roles as onsite tech lead Practiced Agile methodologies in project execution

AWARDS

Innovator of the year – (2012) Employee of the Quarter - Q3-

(2013)

Delivery Leader of the Quarter – Q1 (2017)

HOBBIES

Music

Reading

Carpentry

Travel

Movies

PROGRAMMER ANALYST • COGNIZANT TECHNOLOGY SOLUTIONS •

NOV 2010 - JUN 2013

LOCATION: India, UK.

Worked as solo contributor for one of the largest banking organization in the U.S.A delivering applications on Push Messaging and accessibility.

Played a major role in rolling out the first mobile banking application of a major UK based Bank.

Worked on organizations internal initiatives like Near Field Communication and Smart store.

PROJECT ENGINEER • WIPRO TECHNOLOGIES LTD •

AUG 2008 - NOV 2010

LOCATION: India, UK.

Worked mostly as a developer on BREW and Android platforms releasing handsets for major mobile handset manufacturers

EDUCATION

B. TECH • 2008 • WEST BENGAL UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY •

Completed B. TECH. in Computer Science and Engineering with a DGPA of 8.3

ISC • 2004 • COUNCIL FOR THE INDIAN SCHOOL CERTIFICATE EXAMINATIONS

Completed my higher secondary education with Science major with an aggregate of 86%.

SOCIAL

STACK OVERFLOW

An active member of stackoverflow and contributor. Can be found by the name of "amiekuser" or through http://stackoverflow.com/users/544631/amiekuser

LINKEDIN

I can be found on linked in if searched by "Tamal Bhattacharya" or by clicking on https://in.linkedin.com/in/tamal-bhattacharya-b4253432